<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kelsey Marcott</title>
    <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kelsey Marcott</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 12:52:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kel-c-lm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Good UX: 10 Usability Heuristics</title>
      <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/blog/uxone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 12:52:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/blog/uxone/</guid>
      <description>Good UX can be hard to define, because there are no hard and fast rules that define good UX. A user&amp;rsquo;s experience is, after all, going to be highly dependent on the user, and one user&amp;rsquo;s tastes and preferences will almost certainly never match up exactly to another&amp;rsquo;s. Every user is different. That&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s important to have a set of guiding principles, to inform your UX design.
Luckily, we don&amp;rsquo;t have to start from scratch; such sets of guiding principles already exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old English Meets New Technology</title>
      <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/blog/old/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 22:10:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/blog/old/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I bring this project up to people they always respond with something along the lines of, “Old English…You mean, like Shakespeare?” I don’t, actually. Much as it may not seem that way to us, Shakespeare’s writing is actually an example of Early Modern English. “So, Chaucer?” Nope. Chaucer was Middle English. Think Beowulf. Just not the one with Angeline Jolie.
Old English was spoken in gasp England between around 55 BC to around 1100 AD, and it wasn’t anything like the English you, I, Shakespeare or Chaucer speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Essay</title>
      <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/formalessay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/formalessay/</guid>
      <description>This sample represents a formal essay, originally completed for a course at Aarhus University. The essay is done in APA style, and a sample of the first few pages can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help - What is a Gemfile?</title>
      <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/educative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/educative/</guid>
      <description>This is a short reference piece that I contributed to Educative.io&amp;rsquo;s Edpresso series. Before writing this piece, my experience with Ruby had been limited; I therefore considered this a research challenge. After carefully reading through enough documentation to be sure that I understood the concepts, I was able to communicate them clearly, and concisely enough to fit into Educative&amp;rsquo;s short-form Edpresso format. The finished product can be seen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Guide - Basil Bookseller Software</title>
      <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/user-guide-basil-bookseller-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/user-guide-basil-bookseller-software/</guid>
      <description>During my time at Copperfield&amp;rsquo;s Books, I was asked to produce a document to facilitate the training of new employees. The document serves as a how-to guide, and covers receiving new shipments, both from vendors, and from other Copperfield&amp;rsquo;s locations, as well as vendor returns. It includes both quick start guides for easy reference, as well as detailed instructions for training purposes.
The document was created in Microsoft Word, and was used successfully to train new hires, as well as to train current employees on new skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walk-Through - Simple Machine Translation</title>
      <link>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/translator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kel-c-lm.github.io/samples/translator/</guid>
      <description>My favorite project that I completed during my time at San Francisco State University was my capstone project in linguistics. The professor allowed us quite a bit of artistic license when it came to our write-ups, and we were able to largely define our own projects, as long as they met a certain set of criteria. I chose a project centered around machine learning; specifically machine translation. I assembled a corpus, created a model, and presented my work in an interactive write-up in the form of a Google CoLab notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
